poets.org 2019-06-07

# Privacy Policy | Academy of American Poets

We are committed to protecting your privacy and the privacy of any personally identifiable information that we collect.

**Information We Collect**  
For each visitor to our website, our web server automatically recognizes only the visitor’s domain name and not the visitor’s email address.

We collect the following:

  * only the domain name and not the email address of visitors to our website;
  * aggregate information about which pages visitors access or visit;
  * information volunteered by the visitor, such as email addresses of those who register with our website, sign up for our e-newsletters, become members, or make donations; or personal information collected via surveys. 

**Use of This Information**  
The information we collect is used to improve the content of our website and to notify users about updates to our website.

We do not rent, sell, or share email addresses with any organization. We do share email addresses of those who sign up for our e-newsletters with the third-party platform Campaign Monitor (see **Third-Party Platforms** ).

If you supply us with your postal address online you may receive periodic mailings from us with information about new services and/or upcoming events. From time to time, we make mailing addresses of our past and current members available for rent to our peer literary organizations for postal mail solicitations. If you do not wish to receive any mailings from us and/or if you would like your mailing address excluded from any future list rental, please let us know by calling (212) 274-0343, ext. 11, emailing [membership@poets.org](mailto:membership@poets.org), or sending a letter to the address below.

Persons who supply us with their telephone numbers online will only receive telephone contact from us with information regarding orders, payments, or accounts they have made online.

**Correcting This Information**  
Upon request we provide site visitors with access to unique identifier information (e.g., customer number, user ID, and password) that we maintain about them, transaction information (e.g., dates on which customers made purchases, amounts, and types of purchases) that we maintain about them, and contact information (e.g., name, address, phone number) that we maintain about them.

Users may access this information and/or have inaccuracies corrected in this information by calling (212) 274-0343, ext. 11, emailing [membership@poets.org](mailto:membership@poets.org), or sending a letter to the address below.

**Opting Out**  
You may unsubscribe from our e-newsletters at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe here” link, which appears at the bottom of every e-newsletter. You may also let us know that you do not want to receive email from us in the future by calling (212) 274-0343, emailing [academy@poets.org](mailto:academy@poets.org), sending a letter to the address below.

**Cookies**  
We use cookies to store visitors preferences and to record session information.

**Third-Party Platforms**  
All donations made to the Academy of American Poets are processed by a secure third-party software called **Blackbaud**. Credit card information is not retained by the Academy of American Poets except for recurring donations, which are encrypted by the software. Email addresses for all donors and members whose gifts are processed online are automatically enrolled in the Academy of American Poets’ bimonthly e-newsletter; donors may unsubscribe at any time (see **Opting Out** ).

The Academy of American Poets’ email campaigns and newsletters are sent using **Campaign Monitor**. Refer to [Campaign Monitor’s Privacy Policy](https://www.campaignmonitor.com/policies/#privacy-policy) for more information about how it handles subscriber data.

The Academy of American Poets does not store credit card information on our website or servers. All payments through our online store are processed by the secure third-party platform **Shopify**. The [Shopify Privacy Policy](https://www.campaignmonitor.com/policies/#privacy-policy) describes the information it collects during a transaction. 

The Academy of American Poets uses **Submittable** to manage submissions to some of our awards, such as the Walt Whitman Award. View [Submittable’s Privacy Policy](https://www.submittable.com/privacy) for more information about how it handles data.

The Academy of American Poets uses numerous social media platforms to inform and interact with followers. The Academy of American Poets does not share any user data with any of these platforms. The platforms use cookies and/or pixel tracking to serve ads to users. You can view their privacy policies for more information: [Google](https://policies.google.com/privacy), [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/), [Twitter](https://twitter.com/en/privacy), [Pinterest](https://policy.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy), and [Instagram](https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388).

The Academy of American Poets web servers are hosted and managed by Platform.sh. The [Platform.sh Privacy Policy](https://platform.sh/privacy-policy) describes how it handles data.

The Academy of American Poets runs advertisements on Poets.org through **DoubleClick for Publishers** and (via Litbreaker, a third-party ad network) **NUI Media**. We run nonpersonalized ads, which are ads that are not based on a user’s past behavior. The ads are sometimes targeted using contextual information, including coarse geo-targeting based on current location (at the city-level, but not at the ZIP/postal code-level). We do not run ads that rely on interest-based audience targeting, i.e., demographic targeting or user list targeting. Although nonpersonalized ads don’t use cookies or mobile ad identifiers for ad targeting, they do still use cookies or mobile ad identifiers for frequency capping, aggregated ad reporting, and to combat fraud and abuse.

**Updates to This Policy**  
If our information practices change at some time in the future we will post the policy changes to our website to notify you of these changes, and we will use for these new purposes only data collected from the time of the policy change forward. If you feel this site is not following its stated Privacy Policy, please let us know by calling  (212) 274-0343, emailing [academy@poets.org](mailto:academy@poets.org), or sending a letter to the address below.

Mailing Address:  
Academy of American Poets  
75 Maiden Lane, Ste. 901  
New York, NY 10038

Phone: (212) 274-0343  
Email: [academy@poets.org](mailto:academy@poets.org)
